<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Academic</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/</link><atom:link href="https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>{2021}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/images/icon_hu67156ce36ff7ee509cd10a04dec50ed5_3656_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/</link></image><item><title>DARE Project</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/dare/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/dare/</guid><description>&lt;p>The DARE platform provides all the necessary tools to research developers to develop and execute their experiments written using either the fine-grained workflow specification library dispel4py or CWL. Moreover, the DARE platform offers data provenance to the users so as to track and analyze their data. The DARE platform is cloud-ready, integrating containerized software applications running on top of Kubernetes. Kubernetes enables automated deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. Research developers can interact with the DARE platform by making use of its RESTful API. DARE API is a composition of RESTful Web APIs exposed by the containerized versions of the underlying DARE platform components. For more information about the DARE Project visit our site at &lt;a href="http://project-dare.eu/">http://project-dare.eu/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DebateLab</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/debatelab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/debatelab/</guid><description>&lt;p>DebateLab intends to pioneer research towards unlockng the potential of the new dialectical nature of the Web, relying on the coupling of mature fields namely Computational Argumentation, Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval, Machine Learning, and the Semantic Web. The aim of DebateLab is dual purpose; a) conduct research towards devloping the required thoeoretical infrastructure for representing, mining and reasoning with online arguments, and b) develop and deliver a suite of tools and services (e-journalism domain) supporting the uptake and initial exploitation of the related technologies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FAIR4Fusion Project</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/f4f/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/f4f/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked in the FAIR4Fusion project as a Software Engineer. The project&amp;rsquo;s goal was to
make European (or nationally when permitted) funded data more widely available to the
fusion community, other science communities, funding bodies, and the public at large in
order to maximise the impact of, the data and demonstrate the importance of the work
done at relevant sites. I was involved in the development of a demonstrator, written in
python using the Django Framework.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>G.N.T. Information Systems S.A.</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/gnt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/gnt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked as a Software Engineer implementing multiple projects using Java EE/Spring
frameworks for backend services(EJB3,Spring Framework, Hibernate, RESTful and SOAP
web services), with test-driven approach (JUnit and integration tests).
Participated also in UI projects written with Vaadin and Android frameworks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VoiceWeb S.A.</title><link>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/voiceweb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthemeli.gitlab.io/academic/project/voiceweb/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked as a Software Engineer designing and developing speech recognition and
NLU/NLP applications. Additionally, I was responsible for the redesign and implementation
of the company’s products (Dialog Manager and NLI platform) to follow the micro-services
architecture paradigm. I have implemented various improvements on the application’s
datalayer, created a Rule Engine using MongoDB in the backend - the product was parsingXMLs
for rule extraction, implemented a completely new RESTful Web Service for the Dialog
Manager application. Moreover, I have redesigned and implemented a new UI from scratch for
the NLI platform product.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Technologies used included Python, Java, Spring Framework, Spring MVC, RESTful and SOAP web services, Vaadin and others&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>